Jessika Parman

jessika@jessikaparman.com

(805) 249-8353

Experienced office and warehouse manager with a focus on improving workflow efficiency by leveraging automation and digital solutions.

Summary

Jessika Parman is an experienced office and warehouse manager with a focus on improving workflow efficiency. Having learned the ropes of office management in high school while working in her mother's store after classes, Jessika understands what it takes to *think like an owner*.

Jessika understands how modern technology can streamline the efficiency of the workplace. She implicitly understands the pitfalls of "We've always done it this way" and has a sixth sense about how to streamline operations. Jessika understands that the best way to move things forward is to first listen and understand how things work before suggesting solutions which may not fit. But by letting computers do what computers are good at, we can free up the staff to focus on what *humans* are good at.

With experience being forklift-certified, to understanding customer relationship management (CRM) software, to designing inventory control processes, Jessika is truly a *Jill-of-all-trades*. She is intrinsically motivated, thinks like an owner, delivers on commitments, and always desires to deliver the best possible experience for customers. Outside of work, Jessika lives north of Seattle with her husband, two high-school aged children, and three dogs. She is a ranked player in the <u>American Poolplayers Association</u>, and is working on getting her personal training certification in physical fitness.

Skills and Software

While my experience and personal interests are broad, the following list is focused more on my interest in office management and automation, and warehouse management roles. I would be happy to share additional experience for other areas upon request.

- Efficiency Methodologies: Kanban, Lean
- Industries: General construction, flooring, bark/rock blowing, synthetic turf
- Languages: Spanish (partial)
- **Software:** macOS, iOS, Windows, Microsoft Office (classic), <u>Office 365</u> (online), Google's <u>G Suite</u> (online), <u>Quickbooks</u>, <u>Joist</u>, <u>Copper</u> (née ProsperWorks)
- Office: Accounting (payable & receivable), managing sales bids and budgets, customer engagement, handling payroll, managing social media presence.
- Warehouse: Receiving and validating inventory, scheduling workers and resources for customer jobs, loading trucks for customer jobs, certified for forklift training and safety.

Work Experience & Notable Projects

Bark King Blower Truck Service — Woodinville, WA

Office Manager (January 2019—Present)

- Improved the the interview process to have fewer false-positives. Adopted revisions to the employee manual, insurance manuals, and training guides. Collaborated with H.R. company to ensure legal compliance. Invested in ensuring employees were engaged, happy, and productive. Wanted to implemented safety meetings, checked equipment, and ensure proper outfitting for the job (e.g., raingear, high-visibility vests).
- Saved money through price comparisons, and negotiating with vendors over prices.
- There was active resistance to digital solutions. While many of these are still unimplemented, I proposed meaningful improvements to our productivity by:
 - Moving the job schedules into a shared, digital calendar that was reviewable by everyone.
 - Moving documents and spreadsheets into a modern office-document solution like Google Docs or Microsoft Office 365.
 - Speed up the ability to pay by migrating from paper invoices being snail-mailed to customers, over to web-based invoicing.
 - Adopting a CRM would have made it easier to divide the work and respond to customer requests in a more timely manner.
 - Migrating from hand-written orders to computer-based entry.
- Wanted to explore having a professional-grade online presence, presence at trade shows, email marketing, coupons.
- Wanted to receive training for the office tasks that the owner "owned". Wanted to increase the cross-training, and follow the <u>Kanban</u> style of working together against a shared queue of tasks.
- Transparent communication with employees is vital to smooth operations; paying attention to customer touchpoints; poor customer communication and a lack of timeliness leads to lost business and customer distrust; better delegation can make the office more efficient; learned that an inability to adapt, thinking small, having a big ego, and micromanagement will actively prevent the success of your business.

Thermo Tech Coatings — Monroe, WA

Office Manager (November 2018-January 2019)

- Managed the office + production floor + 15 employees. Worked with powder vendors to become knowledgable enough to train. Scheduled training seminars to perform demos and teach techniques.
- After a fire, scheduled fire department inspections to ensure we were up-to-code and had appropriate safety equipment. Took the initiative to step-in and address production issues, assigned tasks, performed quality control and training on-the-fly. Met deadlines in a "powder keg" environment and was able to handle the stress of the production floor.

- Took over responsibilities for customer callbacks, qualifying customers and pre-sales leads. Managed the in-house ordering system, the order forms/processes, invoicing, and account reconciliation.
- Employees look up to the people in charge. Operating with transparency and without ego is key to happy/trusting teams.

Synthetic Turf Northwest — Monroe, WA

Office Manager (February 2017–November 2018)

- Adopted the <u>Lean</u> methodology (including <u>Kanban</u>) to eliminate waste and increase organization and efficiency. Performed the intitial inventory of all items and designed a process to keep track of where inventory was used. Optimized the re-order workflow. Inventory management was required across multiple locations. Negotiated with vendors for better pricing.
- Worked with logistics companies to ensure on-time deliveries; performed quality control to ensure customer satisfaction; materials were project-specific. Ensured that we always had the correct materials on-hand for jobs, and avoided tying-up unsellable inventory. Sold leftover scrap materials online. Operated the turf cutter so that we could cut-to-spec.
- Vendor events: Performed cost analysis, booth design and supplies, and scheduling the booth team/equipment. A \$2,500-5,000 event generated 50 leads (avg). Roughly 10-15 were qualified leads that converted into sales (\$5,000 minumum). Up-sold additional products and services.
- Completed a full CRM implementation. Managed the sales funnel from the website, and engaged with customers to qualify the leads. Aligned with owner's vision for online leads, filter of hot/cold leads, and setting-up consultation appointments.
- Participated in "360-degree" performance reviews (self-review, reviewed manager, reviewed peers).
 Review feedback was well-rounded and multi-directional.
- Learned that Kanban doesn't work if there's no accountability/reinforcement; learned the importance of a good workflow; learned the value of self-reflection and understanding your personal strengths/weaknesses; learned that team morale is critical (e.g., team outings); learned the value of earning the trust of your peers (e.g., we all rise and fall together).

A Better Handyman — Mountlake Terrace, WA

Office Manager (December 2016–February 2017)

My job was to keep the office organized and running for a husband & wife-managed business.

- Discovered an interest in inventory management; started the process of organizing the inventory onhand; developed processes for not running out of stock, and keeping track of inventory as it was pulled.
- The owners had an approach to running their business that was incompatible with my personal ethics. Chose to leave after a few months to explore other opportunities.

Contract Furnishings Mart — Seattle, WA

Office and Warehouse Manager (November 2016–December 2016)

I had just moved to the state, and was looking for a job to supplement my income while my fledgling business was still new and unstable. Coming from a warehouse background, I natually gravitated to a team like CFM.

- The store was brand-new and I helped with the store's opening: I designed and set up the warehouse layout and organization; handled all of the loading and unloading of new product from the trucks; started learning the CRM tooling.
- Even though the job didn't work out as well as I'd hoped for, there were some important lessons I learned from this experience: I wasn't prepared for the hour-long commute at 6am into Seattle; learned the importance of getting all verbal agreements in writing; learned the importance of honoring your verbal commitments.

Blazing Gypsy Boutique — Online

Owner, Direct Sales (July 2016-January 2019)

Opened an online retail clothing store for the first time. Even though the business ended up being a failure, I was able to gain insight and experience as a result that is difficult to learn in other contexts.

- Vetted and brought-on vendors; vetted and tested products before selling them; learned the value of building trust with customer relationships; learned how to run a small business end-to-end; learned how to separate personal finances from business funds.
- Explored a variety of approaches to marketing and social media presence via trial and error; managed multiple social media channels with automation; kept customers engaged via email marketing, trade show and vendor events, and Facebook Live video streaming.
- Learned about the cyclical nature of online sales; adapted inventory control to keep the right amount of the right products on-hand, and reduced the off-season products to free-up cash to reinvest; adapted to identifying product 2–3 seasons ahead; over a long enough timeline, was able to see trends about what sells best during different parts of the year. Learned how to analyze sales numbers to understand costs, revenue, and profits.
- Learned humility by discovering several approaches that don't work; learned how to manage and prioritize time while balancing the needs of the business, family, and myself; learned not to employ your friends; persevered when the work got hard and managed to build a business with decent revenue for its size; at the same time, understanding the sales projections helped me understand when it became the right time to close shop. (You need to know when to quit so that you can shift your efforts to something more effective.)
- When you have a product you're passionate about, it's easy and fun to sell; I learned a lot from the many new people I met as a result; gained many personal and professional contacts/connections; the business opened doors to modeling and fitness opportunities.

Floor Connection — Arroyo Grande, CA

Office Manager (June 2015-July 2016)

Currently rewriting. Description TBD.

Project Manager (December 2014-June 2015)

Currently rewriting. Description TBD.

Warehouse Manager (April 2014–December 2014)

Currently rewriting. Description TBD.

Truncated

Earlier experience is available upon request.

Certifications & Accomplishments

- Student guest speaker for the 2007 Arroyo Grande High School graduation ceremony.
- Forklift certificatation; both usage and training.

Education

<u>National Academy of Sports Medicine</u> — Online

• Certified Personal Trainer (NASM-CPT) Program, 2019-Present

Heald College — Fresno, CA

- Major: Criminal Justice, 2010.
- Related coursework: procedures, medical terminology, psychology.
- Completed 2 semesters; Unenrolled after wanting to change major.
- Heald College's parent company (Corinthian College) folded in 2015.